Rohit Rana

Sen. DevOps Engineer Mob: **+91 8059484322**

Preferred Location: **Anywhere** Email: itsrohitsinghrana@gmail.com

Total Experience: 6.3 Years

<u>Career Objectives:</u> Seeking a challenging and rewarding career in LINUX Cloud as professional where I can nurture my skills and knowledge for growth and development of the organization as well as mine.

Executive Summary:

Red Hat Certified Engineer (RHCE) with overall 6.3 years of experience in Linux & DevOps Engineer. Proficiency in managing configuration, maintenance, migrations of large-scale engineering systems and application software & hardware devices with a focus on systems / network administration including diverse networking setups. Expertise in assessing & mapping requirements and translating these requirements into techno functional specifications, custom designing solutions, troubleshooting for complex information systems management by following the followed the standard guidelines.

Certification:

 AWS Certified Solutions Architect – Associate Validation Number: P9J5H8TKJ21E1GS2

• Red Hat Certified System Administrator.

Certificate Number- 130-139-058

Red Hat Certified Engineer.

Certificate Number- 130-139-058

Technical Skills:

- Configuration and Management of Amazon Web Service.
- Configuration and Troubleshooting Resources of OpenStack Cloud.
- Configuration and Managing Docker, Kubernetes and OpenShift.
- Configuration and Troubleshooting of Linux System and Network.
- Configuration, Management and Troubleshooting for Apache Web Server.
- Configuration, Management and Backup of MySQL.
- Configuration and Management of Dell SonicWALL Firewall.

Work Experience:

- Jan 2019 to Till Now with Mount Talent Consulting.
- Feb 2016 to Sept 2018 with AFFLE Technologies Pvt. Ltd.
- July 2015 to Feb, 2016 with KVIT Solution Pvt. Ltd.
- Oct. 2013 to July, 2015 with FLIPKART Internet Pvt. Ltd.

Key Result Areas:

- Maintaining systems by managing product and capability roadmaps, establishing maintenance procedures, and working with systems administrators and other engineers to perform regular maintenance operations.
- Offering technical support to development teams and deploying application on servers.
- Scheduling Cronjob, performing maintenance, back-ups and system upgrades including service packs, patches, hotfixes and security configuration issues raised by clients.

Significant Accomplishments: -

- Operating Systems: Centos, RedHat, Ubuntu and Windows server
- Cloud: AWS, GCP and Azure
- Webserver: Apache, Nginx, Tomcat and IIS server.
- VCS Tools: Git, Bit-Bucket, GitHub, GitLab.
- Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, MSSQL, PostgreSQL, Redis, Elasticsearch.
- Databases Tools: PgAdmin4, MySQL Workbench, and Mongo 3T.
- Management Tools: Open Project
- CI/CD & Build Tools: Jenkins, Maven and Bamboo.
- Automation Configuration Tools: Ansible and Puppet.
- Monitoring Tools: Nagios core, Zabbix and ELK Stack.
- Containerization: Docker and Kubernetes.
- Scripting Language: Bash shell and Python Scripting.

Mount Talent Consulting: (DevOps Engineer) Jan 2019 to till now.

- Configuration & Managing AWS, GCP and Azure Resources.
- Managing Automation Tools, GitLab's, Jenkins, Ansible, Open Project and Docker Container & Kubernetes.
- Managing Web Server, Database, and all type Linux & Windows Server.
- Managing PF Sense Firewall & Network.
- Troubleshooting L2 and L3 Level Issue of Network, and all types of Operating Systems & Server.
- Monitoring all type Server and Databases.

Project: - Rozgar.com, Value Innovation labs, CCIL, HRMS portal and ICSI.edu

Affle India Ltd. (Linux Admin) Feb 2016 to 28 Sept. 2018

- Create, Manage and Monitor AWS Resources such as EC2 Instances, Load Balancers, RDS, EBS Volumes, Snapshots, EIP, Route53, S3 Buckets, and VPC.
- Setup Configure and Managing Web Services on EC2 Instances.

- Setup, Configure and Manage RDS Instances and MySQL.
- Monitoring AWS Resources with Cloud Watch.
- Maintain and configure OS-Ticket Ticketing Tool.
- R&D and Testing in OpenStack Private Cloud.
- Managing SonicWall firewall. And Managing Rules, Logs and Bandwidth.
- Troubleshooting all Operating System issues on L2 Label.

At KV IT Solution Pvt. Ltd. (Linux Engineer) July 2015 to Feb 2016

- Configuring and Managing Citrix Xen Server.
- OS hardening, hot fixes and Patches upgraded in Linux Platform.
- Manage and Configure Nagios, Monitoring Servers Infra and Services with Nagios
- Configuring and Managing LAMP, MAMP and WAMP server.
- Configuring & Managing FTP, Samba, Yum Server, Open Fire Chatting server.
- Create and Manage Crontab & Iptables.
- Configure and Managing a MySQL Database.
- Managing SonicWall Firewall in Level 2.

At Flipkart Internet Pvt Ltd. (System Engineer SPOC) Oct,2013 to July 2015

- Configure, Setup and Manage Citrix Xen Server.
- Managing and Migration Active Directory, Domain Controller, Samba Server, DNS Server, and Network Devices.
- Team Handling and Managing 3 sites Engineer.
- Manage and Configure Nagios, Monitoring Servers Infra and Services with Nagios.
- Working with OTRS Ticketing Tool.
- Working with Cyberoam, configuring DHCP in firewall and create rules and manage Firewall in L1 level.
- Configuring and Managing Wi-Fi Zonal director and Access Point.
- Configuring and Managing IP Phones in North Location.

<u>Achievements & Awards:</u> - One-year Outstanding Performance award provided by Acropetal Technologies while working in Flipkart Internet Pvt. Ltd.

Projects: -

Live Project in Bilaspur Location: -

<u>Hand-Held Devices</u>: - Testing Handheld devices for picking process in Outbound operations.

<u>Flipkart Photo Studio (FPS):</u> - Installation and configuration Network devices coordinate with the infra team, I have configured Samba server, FTP, DNS, Open LDAP and Samba3 domain controller.

<u>Large Appliance</u>: - All Network devices are configured & Server and setup and hub room Installation.

Live Project in Pataudi: -

<u>Warehouse Live</u>: - Warehouse went live without any downtime. Installed and configured Server and Network devices

<u>Server Configuration</u>: - Managing and Configure Citrix Xen server, Open LDAP, Samba server, FTP, NFS, & Samba4 domain controller.

Managing and setup all Network Device, Server & Hubs room access.

Education:

• B.SC done from Mahatma Gandhi University.

Training:

- Hardware & Networking Training Done from HCL CDC Delhi.
- RHCE & RHCSA Training Done from Network Nuts Delhi.
- OpenStack CL110 Training Done from Network Nuts Delhi.

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Sh. Onkar Singh Date of Birth : 08-Sept-1989

Nationality : Indian
Marital Status : Unmarried
Sex : Male

Hobbies : Sports, Travelling, Music

Languages : English and Hindi

Declaration

I hereby declare that all the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.

Place: New Delhi

(Rohit Rana)